<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Storm Sorcery 3.0</name>
    <update version="0.0.1">
      <file name="subclass-sorcerer-stormsorcery3.0.xml" url="https://github.com/bundythegrim/aurorabuilder-homebrew/blob/main/sorcerer-stormsorcery3.0.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>

  <element name="Storm Sorcery 3.0" type="Archetype" source="Crown of Kings Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_STORM_SORCERY">
    <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Your innate magic comes from the power of elemental air. Many with this power can trace their magic back to a near-death experience caused by the Great Rain, but perhaps you were born during a howling gale so powerful that folk still tell stories of it, or your lineage might include the influence of potent air creatures such as vaati or djinn. Whatever the case, the magic of the storm permeates your being.</p>
      <p class="indent">Storm sorcerers are invaluable members of a ship's crew. Their magic allows them to exert control over wind and weather in their immediate area. Their abilities also prove useful in repelling attacks by sahuagin, pirates, and other waterborne threats.</p>
      <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_STORM_MAGIC" />
      <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_ELECTRON_SORCERY" />
      <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_STORM_DEFENSES" />
      <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_STORMS_FURY" />
      <div element="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_WIND_SOUL" />
    </description>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description>Your innate magic comes from the power of elemental air.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_STORM_MAGIC" level="1"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_ELECTRON_SORCERY" level="1"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_STORM_DEFENSES" level="6"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_STORMS_FURY" level="14"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_WIND_SOUL" level="18"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Storm Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Crown of Kings Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_STORM_MAGIC">
    <description>
      <p>
        <em>1st-level Storm Sorcery feature</em>
      </p>
      <p>You learn additional spells when you reach certain levels in this class, as shown on the Storm Spells table. Each spell counts as a sorcerer spell for you, but it doesn’t count against the number of sorcerer spells you know.</p>
      <p class="indent">Whenever you gain a sorcerer level, you can replace one spell you gained from this feature with another spell of the same level. The new spell must be a conjuration or an evocation spell from the sorcerer, warlock or wizard spell list, but will no longer work with your Electron Sorcery feature.</p>
      <h5 class="caption">Storm Spells</h5>
      <table>
        <thead>
          <tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
        </thead>
        <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>fog cloud, thunderwave</em></td></tr>
        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>gust of wind, levitate</em></td></tr>
        <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>lightning bolt, thunder step</em></td></tr>
        <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>strom sphere, watery sphere</em></td></tr>
        <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>destructive wave, wrath of nature</em></td></tr>
      </table>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEVITATE" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHTNING_BOLT" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_THUNDER_STEP" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_STORM_SPHERE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WATERY_SPHERE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DESTRUCTIVE_WAVE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_WRATH_OF_NATURE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Electron Sorcery" type="Archetype Feature" source="Crown of Kings Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_ELECTRON_SORCERY">
    <description>
      <p>
        <em>1st-level Storm Sorcery feature</em>
      </p>
      <p>When you cast any spell of 1st level or higher from your Storm Spells list, you can cast it by expending a spell slot as normal or by spending a number of sorcery points equal to the spell's level.</p>
      <p>If you cast the spell using sorcery points, it requires no verbal or somatic components, and it requires no material components, unless they are consumed by the spell.</p>
      <p>The Empowered Spell Metamagic is applied automatically to any spell from the Storms Spells list cast in this way. When you roll damage for a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to reroll a number of the damage dice up to your Constitution modifier (minimum of one).You must use the new rolls. You can use Empowered Spell even if you have already used a different Metamagic option during the casting of the spell.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you cast any spell of 1st level or higher from your Storm Spells feature, you can cast it by expending a spell slot as normal or by spending a number of sorcery points equal to the spell's level. If you cast the spell using sorcery points, it requires no verbal or somatic components, and it requires no material components, unless they are consumed by the spell. The Empowered Spell Metamagic is applied automatically to any spell from the Storms Spells list cast in this way. When you roll damage for a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to reroll a number of the damage dice up to your Constitution modifier (minimum of one).You must use the new rolls. You can use Empowered Spell even if you have already used a different Metamagic option during the casting of the spell.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Storm Defenses" type="Archetype Feature" source="Crown of Kings Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_STORM_DEFENSES">
    <description>
      <p>
        <em>6th-level Storm Sorcery feature</em>
      </p>
      <p>You gain resistance to lightning and thunder damage, and you have advantage on saving throws against being stunned or blinded. In addition, whenever you start casting a spell of 1st level or higher that deals lightning or thunder damage, stormy magic erupts from you. This eruption causes creatures of your choice that you can see within 10 feet of you to take lightning or thunder damage (choose each time this ability activates) equal to half your sorcerer level.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Whenever you start casting a spell of 1st level or higher that deals lightning or thunder damage. Creatures of your choice that you can see within 10 feet of you to take {{level:sorcerer:half}} lightning or thunder damage.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING" />
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_THUNDER" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Storm’s Fury" type="Archetype Feature" source="Crown of Kings Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_STORMS_FURY">
    <description>
      <p>
        <em>14th-level Storm Sorcery feature</em>
      </p>
      <p>When you are hit by a melee attack, you can use your reaction to deal lightning damage to the attacker. The damage equals your sorcerer level. The attacker must also make a Strength saving throw against your sorcerer spell save DC. On a failed save, the attacker is pushed in a straight line up to 20 feet away from you.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet action="Reaction">
      <description>When you are hit by a melee attack, you can use your reaction to deal {{level:sorcerer}} lightning damage to the attacker. The attacker must also make a DC{{spellcasting:dc:cha}} Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the attacker is pushed in a straight line up to 20 feet away from you.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Wind Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="Crown of Kings Homebrew" id="ID_HOMEBREW_CK_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STORM_SORCERY_WIND_SOUL">
    <description>
      <p>
        <em>18th-level Storm Sorcery feature</em>
      </p>
      <p>You gain immunity to lightning and thunder damage.</p>
      <p class="indent">You also gain a magical flying speed of 60 feet. As an action, you can reduce your flying speed to 30 feet for 1 hour and choose a number of creatures within 30 feet of you equal to 3 + your Charisma modifier. The chosen creatures gain a magical flying speed of 30 feet for 1 hour. Once you reduce your flying speed in this way, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You gain a magical flying speed of 60 feet. As an action, you can reduce your flying speed to 30 feet for 1 hour and choose {{wind soul:creatures}} creatures within 30 feet of you that gain a magical flying speed of 30 feet for 1 hour. (1/LR)</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <stat name="speed:fly" value="60" bonus="base" />
      <stat name="wind soul:creatures" value="3" bonus="wind soul" />
      <stat name="wind soul:creatures" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="wind soul" />
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_LIGHTNING" />
      <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_THUNDER" />
    </rules>
  </element>
</elements>
